LYSANDRO CARIOCA BRAGA

Fortaleza, Ceara, Brazil Mobile: +55 85 997-569-542 Email: lysandroc@gmail.com

Software engineer with eight years of experience developing and scaling applications. Outstanding problem solver with an aptitude for troubleshooting and the ability to quickly master new skill technology.

PROGRAMMING SKILLS

- Languages: Javascript, Typescript, Golang, and SQL
- Technologies: React, Jest, NodeJS, GraphQL, AWS, Kubernetes, RabbitMQ, CouchDB and MongoDB

EXPERIENCE

• Stay22

 $Senior\ Software\ Developer$

Nov. 2021 - Present

• Map: Developing the next map generation at Stay22. The API is written in Typescript, Nodejs and GraphQL, and the frontend uses Typescript, React, Mapbox and Styled Components. I also maintain internal common libraries shared between our internal products.

• SysMap Solutions Software

Senior Software Developer

Feb. 2021 - Nov. 2021

o Global Relationship Platform: A new product for Natura&Co to keep tracking of the beauty consultant relationship time in several countries. Implemented an event-driven design architecture to scale asynchronous relationship timing using AWS Lambda, SQS, NodeJS, and Scylla DB. Added new features ReactJS/Nodejs application. I've used Jenkins, Docker, Kubernetes, Grafana and Kibana as a part of the devops process to scale and monitor the application.

• Instituto Atlântico

Senior Software Developer

Apr. 2020 - Feb. 2021

• 3D Printer Dashboard: Developed a system a as service for HP that shows all information about 3D printer usage. Implemented a thin REST layer written in Golang that reads information from the AWS Redshift; Created dashboards from Figma using React, React Hooks, Typescript; Contributed to the internal DevOps organization creating yaml template steps used across multiple teams.

• OSF Digital

Senior Software Developer

May 2019 - Apr. 2020

• **Private Pension**: A solution that offers a private pension fund to customers. Developed a web application from scratch using ReactJS, React Hooks, Context API, RTL, and Styled Components from Sketch UI; Code was covered by 85% of unit testing; Led a team of three developers to build an end to end testing project using the cypress framework.

• Empreendimentos Pague Menos

Fortaleza, CE

 $Senior\ Software\ Developer$

Fev. 2014 - Apr. 2019

• Warehouse Order Picking System: A distributed system and data over CouchDB used to check and validate the picking process using the pick box method. Implemented a sample method algorithm to pick random boxes and reduce issues using Javascript; Optimized routines to clean up the local database on hundreds of workstations using NodeJS; Optimized the picking process from 2 hours to 5 minutes grouping them by transport routes.

EDUCATION

• Technologies in Systems Analysis and Development

Fortaleza, CE

Faculdade de Tecnologia Lourenço Filho

Jan. 2012 - Oct. 2014

• Escola Estadual de Educação Profissional Santa Rita

Maranguape, CE

Professional Technical High School Education

Mar. 2009 - Dec. 2011